collegefactual.com 2019-05-21

# College Factual Privacy Policy

We use Ezoic to provide personalization and analytic services on this website, as such Ezoic's privacy policy is in effect and can be reviewed [here](https://g.ezoic.net/privacy/collegefactual.com).  

Effective: September 14th, 2016

This Privacy Policy applies to information (including personal information) collected about you on www.collegefactual.com and my.mediafactual.com ("Sites") by BrightHub, Inc. d/b/a Media Factual and College Factual ("Media Factual"), 270 River Street, Suite 405, Troy, NY 12180, +1 (518) 362-7605, info@mediafactual.com.

By using the Site, you expressly consent to our Privacy Policy and accept the Sites’ Terms and Conditions. By using our Sites you consent to the collection and use of your information as disclosed in this Privacy Policy. If we collect information from or about you, we will use it according to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time the information is gathered. Please be aware that our Privacy Policy may be changed by updating this page. You should review this Privacy Policy periodically to ensure you are in agreement with any updates or changes. If you do not agree with our Privacy Policy, please exit and do not use our Sites

### Children's Online Privacy

We support the protection of children's privacy online under the U.S. Children's Online Privacy Protection Act. The Sites do not intend to collect information from children under 13. If you are under the age of 13, do not provide us with any information or use our Sites. If we learn that we collected personal information from a child under 13, we will promptly delete that information. If you believe that we collected information from a child under 13, contact us at privacy@MediaFactual.com.

## INFORMATION WE COLLECT

### Personally Identifiable Information

We only collect your Personally Identifiable Information (PII) when you fill out forms or surveys on our Sites. The types of PII we collect include: full name, email address, residential address, residential phone number, mobile phone number, credit card account information, user name and password, employer contact information, financial aid information, academic information, active duty or veteran student status, information about physical, mental, or learning disabilities.

### Demographic Information

We also collect Demographic Information when you fill out forms or surveys on our Sites, including: age, date of birth, graduation dates, number of siblings, gender, ethnicity, college choices and preferences, your family’s state of residence, family income and assets, interests, abilities and aptitudes for academic and career pursuits, academic pursuits and choice of majors, educational information, learning styles, and preferences for academic majors, career information, employment choices, and salary preferences.

### Non-Personally Identifiable Information

We and our business partners use cookies and other technology to collect non-personally identifiable information about your use of our Sites, Services, email and online communications, including: browser type, operating system, IP address, UDID, web pages you visited before coming to our Sites, web pages you viewed, links you click, pages on the Sites you visit, and the dates and number of times you visit, event data, metadata, keystrokes, our emails you open, offers or links you connect to from our emails.

To learn more about Cookies, see the Cookies, Web Beacons and Other Technologies section below, or visit www.allaboutcookies.org/cookies/.

 **Information we collect about you from other sources, such as commercially available sources:** We may obtain information about you from other sources, including commercially available sources, such as data aggregators and public databases. The following are examples of information we may collect from other sources: name, postal address, age, income level and financial aid requirements, academic history, test scores, marital status and number of children, your interests such as hobbies and pets, consumer and market research data, purchasing behavior, publicly observed data or activities, such as blogs, videos, internet postings, user generated content, and college tours.

All of the information we collect about you may be combined to help us tailor our communications to you and to improve and enhance our products and services.

## HOW WE USE AND SHARE YOUR INFORMATION

### U.S. Veterans and Active Duty Personnel

We may use the Personally Identifiable Information (PII) and other information we collect from you to personalize your experience, provide content and Services according to your preferences, improve our Sites and Services, provide information tailored to your preferences, quickly respond to your requests, administer our Services, and/or process your requests.

  * We do not disclose, sell or share PII collected from active duty service personnel or veterans (collectively "Veterans") outside of the Media Factual company UNLESS the active duty service person or veteran requests information from a specific educational institution.

### Website Visitors who are not registered for the Sites

We may use non-PII information collected about your visits to the Sites to remember you, personalize your experience on the Sites, improve our Sites and Services, and remember your Sites preferences.

## Registered Website Users including Veterans who request specific college information

We may disclose, sell or share your Personally Identifiable Information (PII) with other people including:

  *  **Veterans who Request Specific College Information.** We will not disclose, sell, or share personally identifiable information (PII) from Veteran students without the Veteran’s express permission. If a Veteran specifically requests information from, or an appointment with, one or more participating colleges or universities, your selected college representatives may contact you by email, telephone, regular mail, in person visits or by other means. We do not control how your selected educational institutions use or disclose your personal information.
  *  **Participating Colleges, Education Consultants and Advisors.** We may disclose, sell, or share the personal information of students who are not Veterans with one or more participating colleges, education consultants, advisors such as parents, high school guidance counselors and/or other third parties that a student opts to share information with for the purposes of that party helping them with their college choices, and other higher education marketers. These organizations may contact you directly by email, telephone, regular mail, in person visits or other means. We do not control how these organizations use or disclose your personal information.
  *  **Third Party Service Providers.** We may disclose, sell or share personal information to one or more third parties with whom we have contracted to provide services to us in which case we will require them to honor this Privacy Policy.
  *  **Affiliates.** We may disclose some or all of your personal information with our parent company, subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under common control with us, in which case we will require them to honor this Privacy Policy.
  *  **Internal Analysis and Operations.** We may disclose personal information for our own internal statistical, design or operational purposes, such as to estimate our audience size, measure aggregate traffic patterns, and understand demographic trends among our users. We may outsource these tasks and disclose personal information about you to third parties, provided the use and disclosure of your personal information by these third parties is restricted to performance of such tasks and subject to confidentiality.

### The California Online Privacy Protection Act (CalOPPA) requires us to disclose:

  * Media Factual does not override your web browser’s Do-Not-Track signals or other mechanisms that allow you to opt out from the collection of personal information and data over time and across third-party websites or online services.
  * Media Factual provides personal information it collects about you to third parties such as colleges, educational consultants and other advisors, and service providers who may also collect information about your online activities over time and across different websites.

For example, we may rely on a service provider to:

  * Fulfill your information and service requests and answer your questions.
  * Register Media Factual users, and deliver our email and mobile messages.
  * Mail invitations and offers, contact colleges, manage payments or take other actions on our behalf.
  * Advise you on your college choices.
  * Analyze data, sometimes combined with other sources, to send more targeted communications to you.
  * Conduct research and analyze data to improve our programs, services and Sites.

In addition, where permitted by law, we may also rely on a service provider to:

Combine personal information about you that Media Factual has collected with personal information about you that our business partners have collected so we can jointly send tailored promotional communications to you. If you prefer not to receive these joint communications, you can always opt out by following the instructions provided in any such communication or by emailing us at privacy@mediafactual.com.

### Other situations.

We may disclose your personal information:

 **Legal and Other Compliance.** We may disclose personal information when we believe it is appropriate to comply with the law; to enforce or apply this Privacy Policy, Terms and Conditions)or our other policies or agreements; to protect our or our users' rights, property or safety; to protect our users from fraudulent, abusive or unlawful use of, our Sites; or if we reasonably believe that an emergency involving immediate danger of death or serious physical injury to any person requires disclosure of communications or justifies disclosure of records without delay.

 **Business Transfers.** We may disclose Personal Information as part of any merger, acquisition, debt financing, sale of company assets or other business transaction. Your PI would continue to be governed by the Privacy Policy in place at the time of the business transfer.

 **Aggregated Information:** We may share aggregated, anonymous information that includes or is based on information about you with third parties. This is information that is combined with the information of other users and does not directly identify you. Depending on the circumstances, we may or may not charge third parties for this aggregated information. We also may not limit the third parties’ use of the aggregated information.

 **User Generated Content.** Some Media Factual Sites enable users to submit their own content for profile pages, to obtain services, and participate in blogs, videos, contests, and other functions. Please remember that any information and content you submit becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal, financial, health, or other information in a submission. Media Factual cannot prevent such information from being used in a manner that may violate this Privacy Policy, the law, or your personal privacy and safety and is not responsible for the results of such postings.

 **Targeted Ad Delivery & Reporting Across Multiple Websites.** We work with Third Party service suppliers that collect additional data and non-personally identifiable information about users who interact with the Sites or our services. We and our Third Party service suppliers log page views and collect anonymous information about your activities and interactions on the Sites, third party websites and in mobile apps for the purpose of delivering ads or providing advertising-related services, including providing a specific advertisement based on a particular type of browser or time of day, statistical reporting in connection with the activity on a website or app, and tracking the number of ads served on a particular day to a particular website or app.

## YOUR PRIVACY CHOICES AND ACCESS TO YOUR INFORMATION

We give you choices about how we communicate with you.

 **Digital / Electronic Communications (examples: email, mobile, social media).** Media Factual sends you service notifications by email when you register on some Media Factual Sites. We may also send you email messages about new services and promotions from Media Factual Sites and services and those of our business partners.

You can stop receiving promotional email messages from Media Factual by following the "unsubscribe" instructions provided at the bottom of the email messages you receive from Media Factual or our business partners. To manage promotional emails, social media notifications, or to correct or delete your Personal Information or adjust privacy settings, access the profile section of your Media Factual account (or your social media privacy settings) and follow the directions there.

Cookies, Web Beacons and other Technologies. We collect anonymous information about you using small computer files that are stored on your computer or device, such as log files, cookies, java script, tags and other technologies that track your activities online, etc., such as persistent identifiers, web pixels, pixel tags, flash cookies, user data files, object storage or clear gifs (collectively, "Cookies"). We use cookies to monitor how the Sites are used and to help personalize your online experience. For example, when you register on our Sites, we may store information in a cookie on your computer about your interests and college preferences. The next time you visit one of our Sites from that computer, our servers use the cookie to recognize you. We can then use the information you provided when you registered combined with your activities on our Sites to provide you with services and assistance with your college decisions.

You can accept or decline cookies. Most browsers automatically accept cookies. To learn more about cookies, including how to refuse cookies on your computer, click these links:

  * For Microsoft Internet Explorer: <http://www.microsoft.com/info/cookies.htm>
  * For Mozilla Firefox: <http://support.mozilla.com/en-US/kb/Options+window+-+Privacy+panel>
  * Learn about cookies: <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/cookies/>
  * Learn about Flash cookies: <http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html>

**Web Beacons.** Web beacons are small bits of code embedded in web pages or in emails. We may use web beacons to deliver or communicate with cookies, to count users who used a tool like Badges or visited a web page, and to understand usage patterns. We also may include web beacons in e-mails to learn if messages have been opened, acted on, or forwarded. You can disable the ability of web beacons to capture information in this manner by declining cookies as described above.

 **Other Technologies.** Examples of other technologies we may use to provide better service to you follow:

 **Web Session Variables.** Information that is passed from one web URL to another as you browse.

 **Browser plug-ins/add-ons.** Additional web components that may need to be installed to enable certain web features on our Sites. You have the option not to install these components.

Third-Party Advertising. We may allow third parties, including business partners and ad networks, to display advertising on our Sites. Some of these companies may place a cookie on your computer to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement. This enables them to understand where you, or others who are using your computer, saw their advertisement and deliver ads that they believe are of interest to you. We do not control these companies' use of cookies. Some of these companies are members of the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI), which offers a single location to opt out of their cookies. Please visit the Network Advertising Initiative's website at: http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp. To manage Google settings visit its website at: http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html.

How we use Cookies, Web Beacons and other Technologies. We use these technologies to provide you a richer and more personalized consumer experience, and to do so, we store your user name in cookies to personalize your experience. For more detail see "How We Use and Share Information".

To access or update your Personal Information, access the profile section of your Media Factual account (or your social media privacy settings) and follow the directions there, or email us at privacy@mediafactual.com.

## HOW WE PROTECT YOUR INFORMATION

We are committed to keeping personal information secure. We have appropriate technical, administrative and physical procedures in place to protect personal information from loss, misuse or alteration. We limit access to personal information to those who have a business need. We keep personal information only for a reasonably needed amount of time.

When we provide your personal information to our Third-Party service providers we require those companies to protect the information and to not use the information for any other purpose.

When we collect or transmit sensitive information such as a credit card number, we use industry standard methods to protect that information.

Nevertheless, no security system is impenetrable. We cannot guarantee the security of our Sites, nor can we guarantee that the information you supply will not be intercepted while being transmitted to us via our Sites and services.

## TERMS AND CONDITIONS

### Express Consent:

Media Factual is able to offer its free services, in part, based on the willingness of our users to be reached by colleges or our marketing partners. Some send brochures in the mail, others reply via email or telephone.

By providing information on a Media Factual website, you expressly consent that Media Factual may collect, process, share, and/or sell the personal information and information we collect about you to colleges, marketing partners and Third Party service suppliers including telemarketing companies who may contact you to offer you free information about colleges, college admissions, scholarships, and offers and promotions designed for students, and expressly consent to be contacted by telemarketers including contact via automatic telephone dialing systems and technology that send telephone calls or text message to the telephone number provided, even if you previously registered on a Do Not Call registry.

### Governing Law:

The Sites are published in the United States. We attempt to comply with local data protection and consumer rights laws to the extent they may apply to our services. If you are uncertain whether this Privacy Policy conflicts with the applicable local privacy laws where you are located, you should not submit your Personal Information to the Sites.

This Privacy Policy and our Terms and Conditions together form your and our mutual agreement for your use of the Sites. We may update this Privacy Policy at any time effective as of the Effective Date displayed above. Review the Terms and Conditions and Privacy Policy from time to time to fully understand your rights and responsibilities when using the Site.
